<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="toSee">What to visit</string>

    <string name="varazdin">Varaždin</string>
    <string name="varazdin_about">About Varaždin</string>
    <string name="varazdin_text">\tImagine a city with peaceful and serene streets, a city which is full of economic, educational, technological and entertaining content, a city which is proud of its title as one of the most desirable places to live in Croatia, city which managed to preserve the medieval magic in the 21. century. </string>
    <string name="spancir">--Špancirfest--</string>
    <string name="spancir_text"> 17.- 26.8.2018. \nACTIVATE YOUR CREATIVITY \n\tThe basic idea of the festival, named “Špancirfest”, is to make sure that during the period of the 10 days of the festival most visitors feel they belong to a particular cultural community that cultivates creative thinking, imagination and freedom of expression. “Špancirfest” gathers both professional and self-taught artists from all over the world. \n\tIt brings together musicians and bands, theatre companies, street performance companies, individual street performers and visual artists (multimedia, painting, product design etc.).\n\tDifferent events during the festival take place at different, mostly outdoor, locations in the city’s baroque centre, which is a pedestrian zone. </string>
    <string name="angels">--Museum of Angels--</string>
    <string name="angels_text">\tAfter nearly three decades of painting motifs of Baroque angels and artistic work under the banner of ‘Varaždin: the City where Angels Sleep’, the Artist Željko Prstec organised a home for his work and that of others around the theme of the spiritual and angelic world.With his exhibitions “The city of sleeping angels” and “Andelinjak” Prstec has turned a new page in his work and has started to add a magical and heavenly touch to the hidden and modest comers of Varaždin. \n\tThis is also the first such thematic museum in the region. The slogan, and the identity of Varaždin, connected to the city of sleeping angels is protected by copyright and this identity is also recognized by the public as part of the “Andelinjak” project. </string>
    <string name="old_town">--Old Town--</string>
    <string name="old_town_text">\tThe Old Town is the most important cultural monument in Varaždin. This gothic-renaissance fortress, which was built and rebuilt several times from 14th to the 19th century, has been home to The Culture and History Department as a part of Varaždin City Museum since 1925. \n\tWhat is special about the display is that there are ten rooms furnished in period style, showing chronologically renaissance, baroque, rococo, Empire, Biedermeier, historicism and art deco. Walking through all these rooms a visitor can experience the spirit of the times gone-by and the lifestyle of those times. </string>
    <string name="angelus">--Angelus Restaurant--</string>
    <string name="angelus_text">\tIts modern and creative cuisine served in a pleasant atmosphere with a specifically rustic space makes Angelus Restaurant Varaždin’s inevitable gastronomic location. The ambience under old arches and walls decorated with angels makes Angelus a romantic story that builds on the idea of Varaždin as a City where angels sleep, and it offers imaginatively designed authentic Mediterranean and continental cuisine that meets the spirit of the new era. A superb selection of dishes is available along with a wide range of pizzas made with hand-made dough and whole-wheat flour. \nInfo:\n\tAlojzija Stepinca 3, tel.+385(0)42 303/-868 </string>
    <string name="sanjek">--Šanjek Snacks--</string>
    <string name="sanjek_text">\t At the entry to the City centre visit Zalogajnica Šanjek which has, over many years, retained its special charm that complements its relaxed and warm atmosphere. It is the oldest fast food shop in Varazdin. They offers traditional dishes from the Varaždin area and specialises in foal and horse meat dishes. \n\tIt is the perfect combination of tradition, good humour and delicious homemade food! \nInfo:\n\t B.Radić 53, tel.+385 42 212/-718 </string>
    <string name="turist">--Hotel Turist Restaurant--</string>
    <string name="turist_text">\tGourmet à la carte offerings from the Hotel Turist bring you a gastronomic story which, thanks to the Golden Croatian Chef, provides irresistible pleasures for true gourmands. The Hotel Tourist Restaurant ranks highly on the Croatian gourmet scene and contributes in different areas of cooking, from homemade dishes from Varaždin to traditional international cuisine dishes, Italian and vegetarian cuisine. \nInfo:\n\t Aleja kralja Zvonimira 1, tel.+385(0)42 395/-395 </string>

    <string name="trakoscan">Trakošćan</string>
    <string name="trakoscan_about">About Trakošćan</string>
    <string name="trakoscan_text"> \tCastle Trakošćan\'s cultural heritage, is protected as a historical entity, which consists of the castle, the building next to the castle, park and forest park with a lake. Today the castle is one of the few facilities in Croatia with preserved its own constitution, historically closely related to the architectural framework and the life of its owners. </string>
    <string name="trakoscanMuseum">--Trakošćan Museum--</string>
    <string name="trakoscanMuseum_text"> \tTrakoscan was built in the late 13th century in northwestern Croatian defense system as a small observation fortress for monitoring the road from Ptuj to Bednja Valley. \n\tAccording to legend, Trakoscan was named after the Thracian fortress (ARX Thacorum) which allegedly existed in antiquity. Another preserved legend says, it is named after the knights Drachenstein who in the early Middle Ages, ruled the region. </string>
    <string name="cross">--St. Cross chapel--</string>
    <string name="cross_text">\tIn Trakošćan park, there is a chapel dedicated to St. Cross. It was built in 1754 in the spirit of Baroque classicism, by donations of Suzana Malatinski, the women of Joseph Casimir Draskovic. Special charm to this small area gives the fact that it is integrated into the entire inventory needed for the equipment of a church: an elevated choir with organ, pulpit, a bench with a raised lectern and altar overlooking the large crucifix. \n\tOutside the chapel is simple, just a facade with bell tower is classified as especially prominent decorations. The interior is divided into equally long rectangle vaulted nave and sanctuary ending shallow apse. </string>
    <string name="lake">--Terrace at Lake Martin--</string>
    <string name="lake_text">\tThe floating restaurant is located at the foot of the castle at the very beginning of the lake. It was built in 1996 and privately owned. \n\tThe restaurant offers food and drink services, and pedal boats can be rented to park a forest and lake park. </string>

    <string name="aqua">Varaždinske Toplice</string>
    <string name="aqua_about">About Varaždinske Toplice</string>
    <string name="aqua_text">\tSmall town in northern part of Croatia in Varaždin County. The town has been well known throughout the centuries for its hot springs as well as a medical center. In Ancient Rome it was known as AquaeIasae.\n\tThe town is also famous for being a site of a school in 1480 which is considered to be the oldest known school in the Balkan peninsula.</string>
    <string name="iasae">--Aquae Iasae--</string>
    <string name="iasae_text">\tAquae Iasae was the Roman settlement and Roman bath in the area of present city Varaždinske Toplice, Croatia.\n\tSpecific conditions of soil around the springs of water, and travertine deposits, have given rise to good preservation of Roman architecture, so that this complex is one of the best preserved Roman sites in Croatia.</string>
    <string name="house">--Country house--</string>
    <string name="house_text">\tCountry house from 1801., on the slope of the hill between the parish hall and department store, this old wooden house is covered with a slam, which is also a valuable monument of Croatian architecture. Today there is an ethnographic collection of the Native Museum in the house. The house was redeemed in one village in 1963, and was here as the founding founder of the Varaždinske Toplice Provincial Museum mr.ph. Josip Čabrijan.</string>
    <string name="hiza">--Đurina hiža--</string>
    <string name="hiza_text">\tDjurina hiža was named after Grandpa Đuri. Grandfather was a woodsman, an alley, collected medicinal herbs, made homemade juices and juices. Grandpa began to love nature and we continue. Mom and daughter work in the kitchen at local specialties. Dad deals with a vineyard with 6,000 trout and produces wine that we help. In addition, Dad produces and cured meat products for Đurinahiža. The son runs the restaurant and cares about development. Đurinahiža is a family story!\nInfo:\n\tVaraždinskaulica 70, VaraždinskeToplice \tTel: 042 668 148</string>
    <string name="vila">--Vila Toplissa--</string>
    <string name="vila_text">\tThe Vila Toplissa excursion is built on the picturesque hill above the VaraždinskeToplice, which offers an overwhelming view of the warm end. Slim dishes of traditional Zagorje cuisine will ensure that your view remains in a long and pleasant memory. Where, once, a very important spa resort and the center of different cultures, today is a culinary offer that is based on tradition, but with the touch of the modern. Their palette of homemade food with a rich offer of the best Croatian wines will take you to the past, because the most important items are the dishes that once baked our grandmothers.\nInfo:\n\tVinogradska 20a, 42223 VaraždinskeToplice \tTel: 042 601 780</string>

    <string name="ludbreg">Ludbreg</string>
    <string name="ludbreg_about">About Ludbreg</string>
    <string name="ludbreg_text">\tThe small town of Ludbreg in north-western Croatia will again be celebrating Centre of the World Day on 1 April. This annual celebration, not an April Fool’s joke despite the date, hasmade this small town famous all around the world. The folk of Ludbreg claim that if you were to spread a map of the world flat, then it is their town which is bang smack in the middle.</string>
    <string name="center">--Center of the World--</string>
    <string name="center_text">\tIn the Trinity Square there are concentric circles of the Center of the World. Every year, during the celebration of the Day of the World Center, circles are set up with tile cities of friends with their names and banners in the background of the fountain.</string>
    <string name="island">--The Island of Youth--</string>
    <string name="island_text">\tThe Island of Youth is a popular promenade that is located almost in the very center of the city and is connected to the small town by a small pedestrian bridge.\n\tThe island is arranged for open-air events, and is part of a whole made up of ponds, embankments and forests, on the south and east side of the river Bednjom, and from the north by the so-called Mill Canal.</string>
    <string name="chapel">--The Chapel of Precious Blood of Christ--</string>
    <string name="chapel_text">\tThe Shrine of Precious Blood of Christ is a sacral facility in Ludbreg, Varaždin County, founded on the veneration of the Croatian Parliament from 1739. It was built in 1996.\n\tIn 1739, the terrible plague was harassed by Moslavina in the estate of Erdoy\'s Counts, which was under the jurisdiction of the Banja Luka. About 4,500 people died during the seven months. The Kuge was in large part of Slavonia. At the Croatian Parliament in Varaždin, in December 1739, a decision was made on the construction of a chapel in Ludbreg, if the Supreme prevented the plague in Moslavina and Slavonia. Ludbreg was chosen because there was an Eucharistic miracle in it in 1411 and it contains a relic of the Blood of Christ. The plague ceased, but the vow was not immediately fulfilled, probably for objective reasons and in time fell to oblivion.\nInfo\n\tVinogradska bb, Ludbreg Tel: 042 819 177 </string>
    <string name="crnbel">--Restaurant Črn-Bel”--</string>
    <string name="crnbel_text">\tOn a small hill above Ludbrega, the famous Črn Bel restaurant dates back to ancient times. It is known for its good gastronomic specialties and tradition.\n\tThe offer is varied, typical for international cuisine, but with an emphasis on local food and wine from its own production. So in the restaurant you can have a good doctor, homemade brandy and cherry liqueur, eat some of the home specialties (SirnuPlatu, Husky steak, Črn-Bel steak \.\.\.), refreshing a glass of quality home-made wine (Rajnskirizling, Sauvignon, Sauvignon Cabernet) in the end it is sweetened by domestic stingers.</string>

</resources>
